Dubber: Rockets Subtitle: Grey
Today, we'll demonstrate how to calibrate the DFRobot electrical conductivity meter (EC meter)
First, we need to upload the calibration sketch to the Arduino board.
This sketch is used for the calibration and normal use
This is the code "EC Calibration"
Sketches and connection diagrams will be released on the product wiki page later
EC meter connects to "A1" and DS18B20 temperature sensor connects to "D2"
Select the right Arduino board and right COM port
Oooops, looking for the right COM port...
OK Got it.
Now upload the sketch...
Now, open the serial monitor
Select "115200" and "Both NL &amp; CR"
Plug the probe in the 12.88 conductivity solution, if everything goes well, you will see the data in the serial monitor
If you find the value incorrect, you can make a calibration
Send "Calibration" to the serial port, and you'll enter Calibration mode
Enter "Confirm" to confirm the calibration result
Enter "exit" to exit "Calibration Mode"
DFRobot - Drive the Future